José San Martin

Professional Summary

I am a student at Duke University planning on double majoring in Statistics and Computer Science. My skills are multifaceted and have been sharpened through challenging course loads and intense internships. I am a technology enthusiast, and I plan on using my skills in software engineering and data science to help underserved communities around the world.

Work History

IBM - Software Development Intern

New York, NY

06/2019 - 08/2019

- Worked primarily under the EIM group at the IBM Global Chief Data Office (CDO). The work included handling unstructured data and leveraging Kubernetes to provide a machine learning service
- Developed a back-end architecture to provide Machine Learning Models as a service to clients. The architecture made use of the Bazel, Docker, and Kubernetes software. The engineering was done primarily on a Linux Virtual Machine with the use of Vagrant
- Other tasks included maintenance of IBM's BIGSQL database via leveraging their catalog API and handling the unstructured data that is pipelined into IBM's Data Lakes

Duke University Computer Science - Data Science Intern

Durham, NC

05/2018 - 07/2018

- Research under Dr. Jeffrey Forbes and Dr. Kristen Stephens-Martinez, Where I prepared a new Data Science course at Duke based on UC Berkley's DATA8. The new course acts as an introduction to the Discipline of Data Science.
- Worked on a Retention Study, which consisted of an in-depth analysis
 of past Duke graduates to create a model of predicting a student's
 chance of retention and success in Computer Science at Duke.
- Database design and population using SQLite3.

hello@josesmo.com 919-753-6779 440 Chapel Drive, Durham, NC 27708

- Portfolio: www.josesmo.com
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-sanmartin-454471144/

Skills

- Data Analysis Scripting Languages (R & Python)
- Object Oriented Programming (Java & Python)
- Back End Development (Docker & Kubernetes)
- Protocol (GRpC & Protobuf)
- Web Development (Express, Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, React.js)
- Database (Postgres)
- Linux and Linux Virtual Machine
- Vagrant

Education

Expected in 05/2020

Duke University

Durham, NC

B.S.: Computer Science and Statistical Science

- Cumulative GPA: 3.6/4.0
- Relevant Courses: Statistical Computing, Computer Architecture, Data Structures & Algorithms, Elements of Machine Learning, Software Implementation & Design,

Duke University - Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Durham, NC 01/2017 - Current

- Teaching Assistant for STA 210: Regression Analysis/STA 101: Data Analysis and Statistical Inference/STA 199: Intro to Data Science / STA 611: Intro To Mathematical Statistics (Grad Version)
- Instruct a weekly lab section, where I assist students in learning statistical concepts, data analysis using the R software, and additional help on the course homework
- Hold dedicated office hours to assist students in coursework material and coding

SEO Career - Success Participant

New York, NY

01/2019 - Current

- Receive 50+ hours of individualized coaching and online instruction to achieve targeted professional developmental goals mainly around technical and soft skills training
- Mastery of fundamentals specific to Data Science in order to maximize the likelihood of a return offer at the end of the summer

- Delivering Software, Mobile Application Development, Graduate Level Machine Learning, Operating Systems
- Member of Duke Undergraduate Machine Learning & Mi Gente
- Recipient of the David M. Rubenstein Scholarship

Certifications

• Web Development BootCamp - Udemy

Extracurriculars

- Director of Operations & Website Manager - Duke Undergraduate Machine Learning
- Peer Preceptor David M. Rubenstein Scholarship
- Linear Algebra Teacher Assistant -Duke Math Department